# TRINIDAD J. GAYTAN

Austin, TX 78729 · (956) 784-9378 · tgaytan14@utexas.edu

Recent graduate of a Full Stack Web Developer course with The University of Texas at Austin. My portfolio showcases recent projects demonstrating my skills. Additional experience includes 9 years as a Technical Support Engineer supporting enterprise software products. This involves troubleshooting software in high pressure scenarios where production systems are impacted and working with development to identify root cause and provide business level solutions.

#### **PROJECTS**

Portfolio – A single page application created with React – https://trinidadgaytan.netlify.app/ Github – My Github profile – https://github.com/tgaytan

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Technical Support Analyst - BMC Software

January 2019 - Present

- Provided Enterprise level support for software that uses Apache Tomcat, Java, C, ,SQL, and microservices
- Handled critical production issues by troubleshooting over a live session and identifying issues with software/system configuration, network, or database
- Subject Matter Expert on Control-M Automation API which allows users to integrate into Control-M using REST API
- Subject Matter Expert on Control-M Web Services which allows users to integrate their REST applications to Control-M
- Selected to be a member of a team coordinating customer facing webinars after leading successful sessions [1] [2] [3]
- Reviewed and published knowledge articles created by engineers and ensured the articles meet our standards
- Guided customer on resolving SSL issues caused by updating the certificate for Apache Tomcat
- Confirmed connectivity with the application and the backend database, such as MSSQL, Oracle database, or PostgreSQL

## Technical Support Engineer II - Forcepoint

July 2017 - December 2018

- Mentored and provided technical knowledge to engineers requiring assistance with support calls
- Served as a point of contact for escalations from managers
- Used interpersonal skills to set customer expectations and deescalate scenarios where customers are frustrated

## Associate Technical Support Engineer – Forcepoint

October 2014 - July 2017

- Provided B2B support for cyber security software designed to filter HTTP/HTTPS/FTP traffic via an on-site proxy or SaaS proxy
- Assisted customers with configuring the proxy to transparently identify all their Active Directory users via Kerberos
- Used Wireshark to analyze packets in customers' network and identify network issues
- Used SQL Server Management Studio to execute queries against the reporting database when reports failed to run

#### **EDUCATION**

# Full Stack Web Developer January 2024

The University of Texas at Austin Online Coding Boot Camp

### **Bachelor of Science, Mechanical Engineering**

May 2014

The University of Texas at Austin

### **SKILLS**

Node

Express

REST API

GraphQL

Git

- React CSS
- NoSQL
  Application Troubleshooting
  - Active Directory
  - MongoDB & Mongoose
  - PostgreSQL, Oracle, MSSQL
  - Linux
  - SSL
- Sequelize
  Zoom/Microsoft Teams/WebEx

- Log Analysis
- Wireshark
- High Availability
- Forcepoint Secure Web Gateway
- Knowledge Capture
- Control-M
- Salesforce
- AWS S3

## **CUSTOMER FACING WEBINARS**

- [1] Connect with Control-M: Activating Communication with Microsoft Active Directory over SSL
- [2] Connect with Control-M: Control-M/Enterprise Manager Internals
- [3] Connect with Control-M: Managing Alerts